J.P. CONIL

Information Technology Leader

CONTACT

Phone

305.206.2693

Email

JP Conil@alumni.brown.edu

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jp-conil

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts Dual

Major: Business Economics
Major: Organizational Behavior &

Management

Brown University - Providence, RI

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Certifications:

- Certified Scrum Master
- Six Sigma Yellow Belt

Applications/Software:

- Hyperion suite of applications
- GL Systems
- Oracle Data Integration
- Salesforce
- Visual Basic (VBA)
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Freshservice
- Sage Fixed Assets
- AcuityLogic

Programming Languages:

- SQL
- Visual Basic

Project Management:

- MS Project
- Clarity

Languages:

- Bilingual - English / Spanish

SUMMARY

An IT leader with extensive Finance knowledge, and over a decade of experience as a manager, excelling at developing talent, and building strong, cohesive teams. A demonstrated history of completing large projects on time and on budget, through the use of strong analytical and communication skills, a focus on efficiency, and the ability to succeed in challenging situations.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE



Senior Consultant

Kadence Consulting. - Miami, Florida

Feb 2018 - Present

- Project Manager for several projects within IT and Human Resources
- Implemented Sage Fixed Assets as a replacement for an Excel based fixed asset process, reducing
 errors and making the close process quicker and more efficient
- Rolled out a new POS system for a national eyeglass retail chain with over 100 locations
- Created the training content for the POS and led training sessions for store managers and associates
- Developed and implemented the POS roll out procedures
- Stood up a new help desk using Freshservice in 5 working days, including a self-service portal, service level agreement (SLA) definitions, priority matrices, workflows, and full agent analytics
- Developed a process for uploading inventory through a web front-end using Robotic Process Automation (RPA)



Director - Salesforce - Pricing and Vehicle Administration Applications

Ryder System, Inc. - Miami, Florida

Mar 2017 - Dec 2017

- Led a team of 20+ employees, 10+ contractors and managed a \$4m budget
- Responsible for a diverse set of applications including cloud-based (Salesforce), mainframe (Vehicle Administration), and on-premises (Pricing)
- Actively managed relationships with the business to prioritize projects, attain high levels of customer satisfaction, and SLA adherence
- Led Ryder's first Agile project designed and implemented a new call center in seven months using Salesforce Service Cloud platform, completed on time and on budget (\$6m)
- Involved in contract negotiations and reviews for projects and software licensing
- Maintained great working relationship with software vendors to ensure maximum utilization of their products
- IT owner for the revenue recognition project, working to ensure timely completion of 2018 & 2019 FASB deadlines



Director – Global Financial Applications

Ryder System, Inc. - Miami, Florida

Nov 2015 - Mar 2017

- Led a team of 15 employees and 3+ contractors and managed a \$5.6m budget
- Oversaw Ryder's financial applications including general ledger applications (Walker), planning and reporting applications (Hyperion), and risk applications (Pyramid)
- Implemented outsourcing solution to relieve single points of failure for legacy applications including mainframe apps using Cobol, Focus and PowerBuilder
- Worked closely with IT leadership to map out the transformation of the company's legacy financial applications

Information Technology Leader

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE CONTINUED



Senior Manager - Hyperion Global Systems

Ryder System, Inc. - Miami, Florida

Jan 2014 - Nov 2015

- Led a team of 6, supporting day-to-day Hyperion operations while simultaneously working on a Hyperion environment redesign project
- Managed the Hyperion suite of applications including HFM, Planning, Essbase, DRM, FDM, ODI and other applications
- Successfully completed Hyperion Redesign (\$5M) and Tax Provisioning (\$0.7M) projects, running simultaneously
- Drove increases in efficiency and lowered costs by reducing server footprint
- Worked with Internal Audit and PWC to implement and monitor SOX compliance
- Implemented a cross training program to alleviate risk of single points of failure
- Managed relationships with third-party vendors and outside consultants



Senior Manager of Financial Planning and Analysis

Ryder System, Inc. - Miami, Florida

Mar 2011 - Jan 2014

- Responsible for the annual business plan, long-term strategic plan, and monthly forecast processes for corporate support organizations as well as total company consolidation
- Financial modeling of strategic plan and initiatives
- Monthly forecast consolidation, including analytical and trend analysis of the business Updated and published the company WACC on a quarterly basis
- Prepared and reviewed Requests for Capital Expenditures (RCE's) Managed the RCE's process for the entire company
- Provided overhead and cost analysis for all corporate support departments
- Provided financial guidance and analysis on ad hoc projects
- · Prepared Board of Directors and Earnings call information for Senior Management and external reporting



Manager of Financial Planning and Analysis

Carnival Corporation and PLC - Miami, Florida

Jun 2005 - Mar 2011

- · Responsible for the maintenance of the company's Hyperion financial reporting database
- Created and maintained automated reporting applications using Excel, Hyperion Essbase and VBA
- Worked with various departments and the CFO to generate the company's five-year financial model
- Worked with Treasury department to generate the company's multi-currency cash flow financial model
- · Consolidated, reviewed and reported on forecast and yearly budgets submitted by eight international cruise brands
- Created financial reports and analysis used in quarterly earnings conference calls, 10Q and 10K filings
- Led the design and implementation of the Hyperion database's migration to the company's new chart of accounts
- Provided ad hoc analysis to senior management

Senior Financial Analyst – Florida Region

AutoNation, Inc - Miami, Florida

Sep 2004 – Jun 2005

- Responsible for reporting financial information for the Florida region to the corporate office
- Created and maintained financial applications for use at the dealership and region levels
- Assisted in the organization's migration from Hyperion Enterprise to Hyperion Financial Management
- Participated in the month end financial consolidation of over 70 automotive dealerships

Senior Financial Analyst – Internal / Managerial Reporting Department

AutoNation, Inc - Miami, Florida

Jul 2002 - Sep 2004

- Responsible for the creation, development and distribution of automated financial reports
- Provided ad hoc analysis and financial reports for various departments
- Created quarterly bonus payout templates to calculate and document Regional staff bonuses
- Assisted the planning department during the annual budgeting process
- Developed custom applications using VBA code, including a dealership compensation application used nationally

O

Independent IT Consultant

Mar 2002 – Jul 2002

- Worked with various clients on the development of custom Visual Basic and Internet applications
- Installed IT networks including routers, servers, desktops and wireless infrastructure

Senior IT Staff Consultant

Next Technology Consulting

Apr 2000 – Mar 2002

- Participated in the entire life cycle of projects including proposals, development, implementation, and delivery
- Responsibilities included programming, business development, client prospecting and talent acquisition
- Worked on projects involving Hyperion, Visual Basic, web design and SQL